# JARED MURPHY

# **DATA SCIENTIST**

☑ jared.m.murphy@protonmail.com 📞 (904) 502-0547 👂 10910 Queens Blvd Apt 7J, Forest Hills, NY 11375

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Data Scientist with a background in Mathematics and Statistics. I currently specialize in Time Series Analysis, and for my most recent project I used ARIMA modeling to test the validity of Covid-19 mortality data released by Johns Hopkins University and the CDC. I am currently working on a project using Random Forest, Gradient Boosting and SVM to categorize the cryptocurrency Bitcoin into an asset class. I will then use that information to help create several predictive models to forecast the price of Bitcoin for 2021.

# **EDUCATION**

University of North Florida June 2013 - Aug. 2015

B.S. Statistics 2015

Springboard Data Science Carreer Track
Mar. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Intensive course in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL

# **EMPLOYMENT**

Self-Employed, Carpenter/Residential Painter, Hudson Valley, NY
Oct. 2016 - Current

Finish carpentry, rough carpentry, drywall, concrete, residential painting

High School Equivalency Instructor, Dutchess Community College, Poughkeepsie, NY

Mar. 2016 - Oct. 2016

Teaching high school math and science to students of all ages

Sales Associate, DSW, Jacksonville, FL Aug. 2010 - Aug. 2015

Customer service, shipping and receiving

#### SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE: Python, pandas, numpy, statsmodels, sklearn

MACHINE LEARNING: SUPERVISED LEARNING: KNN, Linear, Logistic, Multiple Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, SVM,

Precision, Recall, Accuracy, F1, ROC

MACHINE LEARNING: UNSUPERVISED LEARNING: K-means Clustering, Hierarchical Clustering, Mean-Shift Clustering, PCA, Cosine Similarity

MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS: Calculus I, II, III, Linear Algebra, Mathematical Statistics, Probability, Bayesian Methods, Hypothesis Testing, ANOVA

RELATIONAL DATABASES: SQL, MySQL, SQLite

DATA VISUALIZATION WITH PYTHON: matplotlib

# **PROJECTS**

Excess Deaths in United States Counties 02/01/20-10/31/20

May 2020 - Nov. 2020

ARIMA modelling was used to forecast excess deaths in US counties during the time period of 02/01/20 to 10/31/20. Excess deaths were then compared with provisional deaths due to Covid-19 released by Johns Hopkins University and the CDC.

Bitcoin: Asset Classification and Price Predictions for 2021

Nov. 2020 - Current

Random Forest, Gradient Boosting and SVM were used to help discover Bitcoins asset class. Exponential smoothing and ARIMA models were then used to forecast the price of Bitcoin for 2021.

### **AWARDS**

Graduated Summa Cum Laude, University of North Florida

Aug. 2015

Inducted into Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honors Society, Florida Eta Chapter

Aug. 2015

## **VOLUNTEERING**

Kunzang Palchen Ling (Buddhist Center), Carpenter/General Contractor

Red Hook, NY

Construction and maintenance of a Buddhist monastery in upstate New York